hi this video explains the technical
details of the signup context used to
profile customers and Prospects it's a
clip from a launch M video for 2023
release Wave 1 but it's equally relevant
today let's turn it over to thern who
will tell us more about it this is very
cool and we're super excited about this
new feature now let's take a look at how
it works in a bit more detail and a bit
more technical details so coming back to
the profiler on your website this is
just a regular form you would build you
have full control over your website you
can do questions of of different sorts
um the most important thing is that at
the moment the user hits that start
trial or sign up button or whatever you
want to call it that URL that that the
user is pointed to needs to be
constructed by you and there's some
certain elements that need to be in
place for that to work correctly let's
go through those
now now if we analy the sign up URL um
we noticed that it's sort of consist of
two parts that I've marked with
different colors here so the first part
as we saw before is where we go to sign
up to become a Microsoft Custer
Microsoft cloud customer or sign into
our existing ad tenant and this is sort
of a standard way to sign up to a
Microsoft cloud product you'll see the
skew here signifying um which product it
is and the other part where it truly
gets interesting
is what happens after I sign up where I
get redirected to business Central where
the provisioning
starts this is the exciting piece and
let's dive a bit more into that this is
what we call the redirect
URL so if we zoom into the redirect URL
we can see that it's what's called a URI
encoded text it's not very readable but
that's because it has to sort of survive
the uh Journey Through the redirects in
the browser if we decod it we can see
that it's a much more uh readable much
more friendly um uh text string that
makes more sense so it redirects us to
business Central dynamics.com it has a
parameter redirected from signup that
that signifies that to our platform that
hey here was a redirect from the sign up
experience so we can perform certain
actions in our
platform and what you see here marked
with bold is the signup context that's a
new parameter that we're actually using
today uh to determine whether or not a
sign up happened from the Microsoft
website in which case we called it viral
and or if it came from Shopify so a
Shopify Merchant can Discover Business
Central and sign up to a business
Central trial through Shopify that's the
only two scenarios where we use it today
and now we think you could benefit from
this feature as well because it's all
about the context of a signup and a
context is your website even if you have
multiple website multiple Brands you can
have different context for each of
those let's dive one uh one layer
further into the signup context because
this is this is key to
understand the signup context itself as
parameter is also a URI encoded text
that means it's actually double encoded
when you encode the redirect URL don't
worry about all that now this will be in
the documentation uh so you can you can
learn all all about it if we decode the
signup context it's much more familiar
now you see it's a it's a text string in
form of a Json key value
pair what's key here is that you can
determine those key value pairs if you
decide to to use an app to provide the
onboarding experience which of course
you should if you don't want to spin up
just a plain Manila BC trial then there
are certain uh key names key key value
pairs that has to be there but this will
be in the documentation as well so
please check that
out now it gets exciting
because if we look at the signup context
from before in relation to the profiler
you recognize here that we have I've
created for example one key called
interest and the value is basic trade
and another key called previous system
pref system where the value is Excel and
so on you get the idea so whatever you
ask for whatever information you want to
pass into business Central you add it to
the signup context like
this that's all great but how can you
then react to it how can you do what we
saw before where you load a specific
checklist well as yakob said this signup
context information is stored in a
system table inside business Central
it's your job in an app when it's
installed to look at this system table
and figure out if you can recognize the
signup context and if you can um you
need to transfer it to a uh to a base
application table that's also in the
documentation I don't want to Deep dive
too much in that now but very like if we
switch to the next um next example here
now you notice that there's some more
information and here I've added an app
ID in this case it's just a random uh
good of of ones and your example you can
get the app ID from your store listing
on app store it's public information you
can just look it up
um and there are some other information
that has to be present here in the
signup context when you use an app ID
for example you need to have specify a
country code the country code must match
with the country code of the customer's
a and it also much must match with uh a
supported country of your app so there
sort of three things that must be a
match in terms of country this will also
be the
documentation you also need to specify
the end user license agreement
acceptance uh as being true what that
means is uh our apis that will load the
app will not load an app to business
Central if the user hasn't accepted the
end user license agreement that means
that on your website as part of the
profiling experience you need to provide
the user with an option to see that end
user license agreement of your app uh
it's a small detail but it's one of the
workings of of our platform apis
but with this what this enables is that
your app that you specify here will be
loaded as part of the provisioning of
the business Central Standard trial and
ultimately by reacting on the on the
signup context the key value pairs here
uh I'm able to say load this checklist
item because that matches what the user
chose uh in terms of answer in this
profile in
question and there's you can do all
kinds of things here and of course we
will make sure that you can have as much
control as possible over the initial uh
UI here in terms of um uh roles and so
on to learn more visit
aka.ms BC onboarding thank you for
watching
[Music]